guru99.com 2019-08-23

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally identifiable information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

 **What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address or other details to help you with your experience.

 **When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you subscribe to a newsletter or enter information on our site.

 **How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature. 
  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services. 

**How do we protect visitor information?**

We do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards.

We only provide articles and information. We never ask for personal or private information like email addresses or credit card numbers.

We use regular Malware Scanning.

We do not use an SSL certificate

  * We only provide articles and information. We never ask for personal or private information like email addresses, or credit card numbers.

 **Do we use 'cookies'?**

We do not use cookies for tracking purposes 

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly.

However, you can still place orders .

 **Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information.

 **Third-party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

 **Google**

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en 

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.

 **We have implemented the following:**

  * Remarketing with Google AdSense
  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting
  * Demographics and Interests Reporting

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website. 

Opting out:

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

 **California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those inpiduals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy.

\- See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

 **According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously.

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy' and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:

  * On our Privacy Policy Page

Users are able to change their personal information:

  * By emailing us

 **How does our site handle do not track signals?**

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place. 

**Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**

It's also important to note that we allow third-party behavioral tracking

 **COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

 **Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

 **In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

We will notify the users via email

  * Within 7 business days

We will notify the users via in-site notification

  * Within 7 business days

We also agree to the Inpidual Redress Principle, which requires that inpiduals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that inpiduals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that inpiduals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

 **CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

 **We collect your email address in order to:**

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred.

 **To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:**

  * NOT use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
  * Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

 **If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at**

  * Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email. and we will promptly remove you from **ALL** correspondence.

Notwithstanding any other provision, we partner with third parties that collect information across various channels, including offline and online, for purposes of delivering more relevant advertising to you. Our partners may place or recognize a cookie on your computer, device, or directly in our emails/communications, and we may share personal information with them if you have submitted such information to us, such as your name, postal address, email address, or device ID. Our partners may link the nonpersonal information we share with them to the cookie stored on your browser or device, and they may collect information such as your IP address, browser or operating system type and version, and demographic or inferred-interest information. Our partners use this information to recognize you across different channels and platforms over time for advertising, analytics, attribution, and reporting purposes. For example, our partners may deliver an ad to you in your web browser based on a purchase you made in a physical retail store, or they may send a personalized marketing email to you based on the fact that you visited a particular website. To learn more about interest-based advertising in general and to opt out, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. To opt-out of the use of your mobile device ID for targeted advertising, please see <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>.

 **Advertising**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp\))

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.  

Guru99 Tech Pvt Ltd  
F 1012 Titanium City Center  
Ahmedabad, Gujarat 380015   
India  
help at the rate guru99 dot com

Last Edited on 2019-03-27
